Evan Garrett

Wilkesboro, North Carolina, USA 912-312-2193 evang522@gmail.com

Full Stack Web Developer

github.com/evang522 linkedin.com/in/evang522 evanhgarrett.com

-CURRICULUM VITAE-

My name is Evan and I am a Full stack Javascript Developer with experience in the workflow of developing Node.js/React/MongoDB-PostgresQL applications on a team. I have fully developed or contributed to more than 5 applications running in production and honed skills to troubleshoot issues and add new features to any part of the Javascript Stack. I look forward to working on a team and developing great products with clean, documented code and efficient problem solving for customers.

-EDUCATION-

Thinkful Engineering Immersion, November 2017: Full Stack Javascript Bootcamp

- 6 month intensive education in best-practice workflow developing Full-Stack MongoDB/PostgresQL, Express.js, React, Redux, Node applications.
- Data Science and Algorithms course focusing computer science, algorithm runtime complexity, and efficiency in data processing.

Toccoa Falls College, May 2014: Bachelor of Science, Philosophy, Cum laude

- Focus on Analytic Philosophy, Philosophy of Religion, Metaphysics, Politics, and Ethics.
- Activities: Vice President of the Philosophy Club
- Small Group Leader

Savannah Christian Preparatory School: High School Graduate, Cum laude

- Activities: Mu Alpha Theta, Marching Band, Jazz Band, Soccer(Football)

-EMPLOYMENT HISTORY-

Desktop Engineer, Athens Micro, Athens, Georgia - November 2015-October 2017

- Played a considerable tech role in a growing business IT company, supporting over 300 businesses in the Southeast United States.
- Onsite and remotely managing and troubleshooting business computer networks, network technology, web, ftp, active directory, and file servers, and performing business disaster recovery ops.
- Enforcing and supporting best practices in computer networks for companies with more than 200 employees.
- Individually responsible for leading proactive and responsive tech support for more than 15 of the company's client businesses.

Front Desk Cashier and IT Assistant, Schlotzsky's; Athens, GA — August 2014 - November 2015

- Worked as a Cashier and, secondarily, an IT consultant.
- Expected to take orders from front counter and drive through, serve food to customers, and maintain dining room cleanliness.
- Maintained Mac technology in the restaurant.

Cabin Director, South Mountain Christian Camp; Bostic, North Carolina — May 2014 - August 2014

- Responsible for leading one cabin of boys per week at South Mountain Christian Camp.
- Provided opportunities for campers to grow mentally and spiritually in the context of the camp's overall education goals.

Student Technician, Toccoa Falls College; Toccoa Falls, Georgia — May 2013 — May 2014

- Maintained Staff, Faculty, and Library Computer Technology.
- Lead college research regarding Library and Staff technology integration, publishing findings in a documented research paper.

Student Technician, Armstrong Atlantic State University; Savannah, Georgia — 2009-2010

• Maintained Computer Lab, Staff, and Faculty computer hardware and software.

LifeGuard, Chatham County Aquatic Center; Savannah, Georgia — 2008-2009

- Maintained the safety of swimmers at the Chatham County Aquatic Center.
- Trained regularly to keep up a working knowledge of First Aid and rescue patterns.

-SKILLS-

Web Development:

Database	MongoDB, Mongoose.js, PostgresQL, Knex.js
	Node.js, Express.js, Socket.io, JWT Authentication
Frontend	React.js, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3
CI & Deploy	Travis CI, Netlify, AWS, Heroku
	Git, npm, yarn, Github, Bitbucket

Business Technology:

Backup	Cobian, Acronis, Dell AppAssure, Dell Rapid Recovery
Operating SystemsWindows	Server, Windows XP-10, Mac OSX- macOS High Sierra, Linux Ubuntu
Ticket Management	
	Passportal, IT Glue
Computer Networking	DHCP, DNS, HTTP, Switch and Firewall
Management	
Organization Management	Active Directory, NTFS and Windows File Sharing, Hosted
Exchange	
Server Management and Virtualization	Hyper-V, Virtualbox, VMWare, Server
Manager	

-PASTIMES AND INTERESTS-

Language Learning

 I have spent a considerable amount of time learning German and Spanish. Though I am not fully fluent in either, I can maintain general conversation with speakers from native Spanish or German speaking countries.

Outdoors Activities

Growing up in the Boy Scouts I spent a lot of time outside, hiking and camping. I still actively participate in outdoor activities such as hiking, camping, and running as regularly as possible.

Drone Photography

I am skilled with building and flying quadcopter drones and producing videos and pictures of beautiful scenery. I have provided paid services filming different venues and providing edited footage.

Philosophy

I attained a degree in Philosophy and I continue to be interested in Philosophy and other academic topics such as History, Science, and Linguistics.

- PROJECTS-

Drystore https://github.com/evang522/drystore Dried food storage and analytics platform for organizing sustenance in emergency situations. Service connecting organizations in need of web work with tech volunteers.

Platform for storing, accessing, and playing back MP3 Links, written in Python.